Guide to the Robert Penn Warren Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1930-85; Series II; 60; (145 boxes)
  - BOOKS
    - Selected Poems, 1923-1975
      - Dust jackets (proofs), n.d. (Box 192, Folder 3381)
      - Editorial material, 1975, n.d. (Box 192, Folder 3382-83)
      - Reviews, 1976-81 (Box 192, Folder 3384-87)
    - Selected Poems, New and Old: 1923-1966
      - Drafts of individual poems: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 192, Folder 3388-3411)
      - Drafts of individual poems: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 193, Folder 3412-14)
      - Draft A (marked "Master Copy": volume 1 and volume 2): typescript, printed text and photocopies, corrected (Box 193, Folder 3415-24)
      - Draft B: photocopies of printed text, n.d. (Box 193, Folder 3425-28)
      - Manuscript fragments: holograph and typescript (Box 194, Folder 3429)
      - Setting typescript, 1966 (Box 194, Folder 3430-34)
      - Galley proofs
        See: Oversize, Box 306, folders 5311-17
      - Page proofs
        See: Oversize, box 307, folders 5318-22
      - Dummy paste-ups, n.d. (Box 194, Folder 3435-38)
      - Notes on poems (unidentified author), n.d. (Box 194, Folder 3441)
      - Dust jackets, n.d. (Box 194, Folder 3442)
      - Front and end matter (Box 194, Folder 3443)
      - Sample pages (printed text), 1966 (Box 194, Folder 3444)
      - Editorial material (Random House), 1966, n.d. (Box 194, Folder 3445)
      - Copyright sheets, n.d. (Box 194, Folder 3446)
      - Reviews (Box 194, Folder 3447)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 194, Folder 3448)
    - Selected Poems of Denis Devlin
      - Source material, n.d. (Box 195, Folder 3449)
      - Typescript (introduction), n.d. (Box 195, Folder 3450)
      - Typescript (poems only), n.d. (Box 195, Folder 3451)
      - Rejected poems: typescript, n.d. (Box 195, Folder 3452)
      - Galley proofs, n.d. (Box 195, Folder 3453)
      - Related correspondence, 1959-60, n.d. (Box 195, Folder 3454)
    - Selected Poems of Herman Melville
      - Research material, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 3455)
        See also: Oversize, Box 308, folder 5323
      - Notes (Box 196, Folder 3456)
      - "A Note on This Book", 1969, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 3457)
      - Introductory Essay
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 3458)
        - Draft A (first draft): holograph, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 3459)
        - Draft B (first typescript): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 3460)
        - Draft C (marked "second draft"): typscipt, corrected (Box 196, Folder 3461)
        - Draft D
          - Copy 1: (marked "Revised 2nd draft"): typescript, corrected (Box 196, Folder 3462)
          - Copy 2: typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 3463-64)
          - Copy 3 (with notes by Willard Thorp): typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 3465)
        - Draft E
          - Copy 1: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 3466)
          - Copy 2 (copy for Southern Review ): typescript, n.d. (Box 196, Folder 3467)
        - Draft F
          - Copy 1: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 197, Folder 3468-69)
          - Copy 2 (marked "final draft" on folder): typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 197, Folder 3470-71)
          - Copy 3: typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 197, Folder 3472-74)
          - Copy 4: typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 197, Folder 3475-76)
        - Setting typescript, corrected (with footnote pages), n.d. (Box 197, Folder 3477-79)
        - Rejected leaves, n.d. (Box 197, Folder 3480-82)
      - Introductory essay (shorter edition)
        - Draft A (marked "early draft 1986"): typescript, corrected (Box 197, Folder 3483)
        - Draft B (marked "duplicate--not revised"): typescript, [1986] (Box 197, Folder 3484)
        - Draft C (with comments by reader for the Ecco Press): typescript, 1986 (Box 197, Folder 3485)
        - "Melville's Poems." The Southern Review, 1967 Autumn (Box 197, Folder 3486)
      - Text of poems
        - Holograph notes (general), n.d. (Box 198, Folder 3487-88)
        - Draft A: photocopies from previous printings, annotated (with duplicates), n.d. (Box 198, Folder 3489-95)
        - Draft B: typescript introduction and notes, with photocopies of poems (Box 198, Folder 3496)
        - Draft C (mixed drafts): typescript and photocopies (Box 198, Folder 3497)
        - Draft D (incomplete): photocopies of printed texts, n.d. (Box 198, Folder 3498-3500)
        - Notes on individual poems (various drafts, unarranged): typescript and photocopies, corrected (Box 199, Folder 3501-08)
        - Notes on individual poems (arranged): typescript, corrected (Box 199, Folder 3509)
        - Notes on individual poems (revised): typescript, carbon (Box 199, Folder 3510)
        - Notes on individual poems (marked "Rejects"): typescript, corrected (Box 199, Folder 3511-14)
        - Manuscript fragments: printed texts, photocopies, n.d. (Box 199, Folder 3515)
        - Setting typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 200, Folder 3516-27)
        - Galley proofs
          See: Oversize, Box 308, folders 5324-27 and Box 309, folders 5328-31
        - Page proofs
          See: Oversize, Box 310, folders 5332-37
        - "Van Dykes" (Box 200, Folder 3528-29)
        - "Van Dykes" (Box 201, Folder 3530-32)
        - Sample pages: printed text, n.d. (Box 201, Folder 3533)
        - Front and end matter (miscellaneous) (Box 201, Folder 3534)
        - Dust jackets (proofs), n.d. (Box 201, Folder 3535)
        - Editorial material, 1970-71, n.d (Box 201, Folder 3536)
        - Related correspondence, 1965-68 (Box 201, Folder 3537)
        - Reviews, 1971, n.d. (Box 201, Folder 3538)
        - Critique of Warren's introduction by H. A. Murray: typescript, n.d. (Box 201, Folder 3539)
        - Miscellaneous, n.d (Box 201, Folder 3540)
    - So Clear, O Victory (unpublished novel)
      - Holograph notes, 1966 (Box 201, Folder 3541)
      - Draft A (Chapters I and II only): holograph (Box 201, Folder 3542-43)
      - Draft B (Chapter I only)
        - Copy 1: typescript, n.d. (Box 201, Folder 3544)
        - Copy 2: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 201, Folder 3545)
      - Draft C (chapter I only)
        - Copy 1: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 201, Folder 3546)
        - Copy 2: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 201, Folder 3547)
    - Thirty-Six Poems
      - Holograph and typescripts (incomplete) (Box 201, Folder 3548-59)
    - Understanding Fiction
      - Incomplete draft: typescript, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3560)
      - Translation (by Warren) of Dino Buzzeti, "L'Uccisione del Drago" ("The Killing of the Dragon"): holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 202, Folder 3561)
      - "I Want to Know Why" (critique): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3562)
      - "The Killers" (critique): typescript, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3563)
      - Publicity brochures, 1959, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3564)
    - Understanding Poetry
      - "Prospectus": typescript, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3565)
      - Introduction: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3566)
      - Contents sheet: typescript, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3567)
      - Partial draft ("Tone and Attitude"): typescript (Box 202, Folder 3568)
      - Suggested revisions to first edition by Cleanth Brooks, [c.1948] (Box 202, Folder 3569)
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3570)
      - Critique, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3571)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3572)
    - Who Speaks for the Negro?
      - Research material
        - Articles, essays, and pamphlets (some with annotations), 1963-64, n.d. (Box 202, Folder 3573-79)
        - Articles, essays, and pamphlets (some with annotations), 1963-64, n.d. (Box 203, Folder 3580-92)
        - Articles, essays, and pamphlets (some with annotations), 1963-64, n.d (Box 204, Folder 3593-98)
        - Articles, essays, and pamphlets (some with annotations), 1944-64, n.d. (Box 205, Folder 3599-3601)
        - News clippings, 1963-64 (Box 206, Folder 3602-09)
        - News clippings, 1956-65 (Box 206, Folder 3610-15)
        - Holograph notes, 1964, n.d. (Box 206, Folder 3616-19)
        - Notebook (Conference on Non-Violence), n.d. (Box 206, Folder 3620)
        - Notebooks, [1964] (Box 206, Folder 3621)
        - Notes and references (notecards) (Box 207, Folder 3622)
        - List of transcriptions of interview tapes (Box 208, Folder 3623)
      - Typescripts of interviews
        - James Baldwin (with letter from Warren), 1964 (Box 208, Folder 3624)
        - Carroll Barker, 1964 (Box 208, Folder 3625)
        - Wylie Branton, 1964 (Box 208, Folder 3626)
        - Will Campbell, [1964] (Box 208, Folder 3627)
        - Stokely Carmichael (with letter), 1964 (Box 208, Folder 3628-29)
        - Stokely Carmichael, Izell Blair, Lucy Thornton and Jean Wheeler, 1964 (Box 208, Folder 3630-32)
        - Joseph Carter, [1964] (Box 208, Folder 3633)
        - Felton Clark (with letter), [1964] (Box 208, Folder 3634)
        - Kenneth Clark, 1964 (Box 208, Folder 3635)
        - Lois Elie, Nils Douglas, and Robert Collins, [1964] (Box 208, Folder 3636)
        - Ralph Ellison, [1964] (Box 208, Folder 3637)
        - Charles Evers (with letter from Warren), 1964 (Box 208, Folder 3638)
        - James Farmer (with letters from Warren), 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3639)
        - James Forman (with letters from Warren), 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3640)
        - Milton Galamison, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3641)
        - Richard Gunn, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3642)
        - Claire Harvey (with letters from Warren), 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3643-44)
        - William Hastie (with letter), 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3645)
        - Aaron Henry (with end of Gilbert Moses interview), 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3646-47)
        - Sarm Henry, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3648)
        - Jackson State College students, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3649-51)
        - Rev. Johnson and Rev. James Peters (incomplete), 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3652)
        - Vernon Jordan, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3653)
        - Martin Luther King, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3654)
        - Montgomery King, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3655)
        - J. M. Lawson, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3656-57)
        - Malcolm X, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3658)
        - Gilbert Moses and Richard Murphy, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3659-60)
        - Robert Moses, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3661)
        - Stuart Nelson, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3662-3)
        - Adam Clayton Powell, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3664)
        - Gloria Richardson, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3665)
        - Carl Rowan, 1964 (Box 209, Folder 3666-67)
        - Bayard Rustin, 1964 (Box 211, Folder 3668)
        - Kelly Smith, [1964] (Box 211, Folder 3669-70)
        - Southern University students (with letter from Warren), 1964 (Box 211, Folder 3671)
        - William Stringfellow, [1964] (Box 211, Folder 3672-73)
        - Tougaloo College students, [1964] (Box 211, Folder 3674-75)
        - Ruth Turner, 1964 (Box 211, Folder 3676)
        - Wyatt Walker, [1964] (Box 211, Folder 3677)
        - T. H. Wheeler, [1964] (Box 211, Folder 3678-79)
        - Roy Wilkins, 1964 (Box 211, Folder 3680-81)
        - Avon Williams, [1964] (Box 211, Folder 3682-83)
        - Stephen Wright, [1964] (Box 211, Folder 3684)
        - Andrew Young, 1964 (Box 211, Folder 3685-86)
        - Whitney Young (with letter from Warren), 1964 (Box 211, Folder 3687-89)
      - Preface to Vintage edition: holograph and typescript, [1965] (Box 212, Folder 3690)
      - Draft A (Chapter I only): holograph and typescript, [1965] (Box 212, Folder 3691)
      - Draft B: typescript and carbons, corrected (Box 212, Folder 3692-3703)
      - Draft C (Chapter V only): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 3704)
      - Miscellaneous pages: holograph, typescript, and photocopies (Box 212, Folder 3705-06)
      - Miscellaneous pages: holograph, typescript, and photocopies (Box 213, Folder 3707-08)
      - Revised or retyped pages, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 3709-10)
      - Correction sheet: holograph, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 3711)
      - Index: typescript (Box 213, Folder 3712)
      - Bibliography: typescript, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 3713)
      - Galley proofs
        See: Oversize, Box 311, folders 5338-40
      - Page proofs
        See: Oversize, Box 312, folders 5341-45
      - Printer's proof (incomplete), 1965 Jan 5 (Box 213, Folder 3714)
      - "The Negro Now" ( Look abridgment), 1965 Mar 23 (Box 213, Folder 3715)
      - "Robert Penn Warren and Ralph Ellison: A Dialogue" (excerpt from The Reporter ): advance proof, 1965 (Box 213, Folder 3716)
      - Editorial material, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 3717-18)
      - Dust jackets (with changes), [1964] (Box 213, Folder 3719)
      - Related correspondence, 1964-66 (Box 213, Folder 3720)
      - Reviews, 1959-84 (Box 213, Folder 3721-27)
      - Miscellaneous, 1965-66 (Box 213, Folder 3728)
    - Wilderness
      - Holograph notes, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 3729)
      - Plot summary: typescript and carbon (Box 214, Folder 3730)
      - Worksheets: holograph, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 3731-32)
      - Draft A: holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 214, Folder 3733-38)
      - Draft B
        - Copy 1: typescript and holograph, corrected (Box 214, Folder 3739-44)
        - Copy 2 (marked "draft 2"): typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 3745-49)
        - Copy 3: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 3750-54)
      - Manuscript pages (marked "revised replacements"): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 3755)
      - Manuscript pages (marked "rejects"): typescripts, corrected, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 3756)
      - Page proofs
        See: Oversize, Box 313, folders 5346-47
      - Dust jacket, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 3757)
      - Promotional material, 1961 (Box 216, Folder 3758)
      - Reviews, 1961 (Box 216, Folder 3759-60)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 3761)
    - World Enough and Time
      - Research material, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 3762-65)
      - Notes: holograph and typescript (Box 216, Folder 3766-69)
      - Draft A (early title: The Confession of Jereboam O. Beauchamp )
      - Copy 1: typescript, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 3770)
      - Copy 2 (with sketch map): typescript, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 3771)
      - carbon
      - Copy 3: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 3772)
      - Draft B ( The Confession of Jereboam O. Beauchamp )
        - Copy 1 typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 3773-74)
        - Copy 2: typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 3775)
      - Draft C: typescript, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 217, Folder 3776)
      - Draft D
        - Copy 1: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 217, Folder 3777-85)
        - Copy 2 (marked "2nd draft," incomplete): typescript, carbon (Box 217, Folder 3786-87)
        - Copy 2 (marked "2nd draft," incomplete): typescript, carbon (Box 218, Folder 3788-91)
      - Draft E: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 218, Folder 3792-3800)
      - Draft E: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 219, Folder 3801-02)
      - Miscellaneous pages: typescript, n.d. (Box 219, Folder 3803)
      - Correction sheets, n.d. (Box 219, Folder 3804)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 219, Folder 3805-14)
      - Galley proofs
        See: Oversize, Box 313, folders 5348-50
      - Page proofs
        See: Oversize, Box 314, folders 5351-54
      - Microfilm
        See: Oversize, Box 314, folders 5354a
      - Title sheet ("duplicate proof"), n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3815)
      - Limitation sheets, signed, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3816)
      - List of recipients of review copies, 1950 (Box 220, Folder 3817)
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3818)
      - Reviews, 1950-51, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3819-21)
      - Critical studies
        - Lee, Young-Oak. "Recognition of Evil: The Scarlet Letter and World Enough and Time" (offprint) (Box 220, Folder 3822)
        - Runyon, Randolph. "The Beach, the Hearth, and the Hidden Name in World Enough and Time ": typescript (Box 220, Folder 3823)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3824)
    - You, Emperor, and Others
      - Holograph and typescript (Box 220, Folder 3825-27)
      - Miscellaneous pages, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3828)
      - Setting typescript, [1960] (Box 220, Folder 3829)
      - Galley proofs (book version)
        See: Oversize, Box 314, folders 5355-56
      - Galley proofs ( Yale Review )
        See: box 314, folder 5357
      - Plate proofs, [1960] (Box 220, Folder 3830)
      - Transcript of poems from You, Emperor and Promises to accompany phono recording of Warren's reading of his poetry (Box 220, Folder 3831)
      - Reviews, 1960 (Box 220, Folder 3832)
    - Untitled Novel
      - Typescript, corrected, [c. 1935] (Box 220, Folder 3833-34)
      - Evaluation (unsigned), n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3835)
    - Notes
      - On writings ( Circus in the Attic, Brother to Dragons, World Enough and Time ): holograph notebook (Box 220, Folder 3836)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    Box 333 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult access services for further information.
    - Short Stories
      - "Blackberry Winter"
        - Typescript corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3837)
        - Printed copy (The Cummington Press), 1946 July (Box 221, Folder 3838)
        - Spanish translation ("La Helada De Las Moras") (Box 221, Folder 3839)
        - Commentaries, 1962-70 (Box 221, Folder 3840)
      - "Cass Mastern's Wedding Ring" (excerpt from All the King's Men ): typescript, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3841)
      - "A Christian Education": typescript, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3842)
      - "The Circus in the Attic"
        - First draft: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3843)
        - Revised draft
          - Copy 1: typescript, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3844)
          - Copy 2 (marked "diluted copy"): typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3845)
        - Second revised draft: typescript, carbon (Box 221, Folder 3846)
        - Printed copy. Cosmopolitan, 1947 Sep (Box 221, Folder 3847)
        - Article on possible source (untitled), 1978 (Box 221, Folder 3848)
      - "The Confession of Brother Grimes"
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3849)
        - Revised draft: typescript and carbon (Box 221, Folder 3850)
      - "Don't Bury Me at All" (with Max Shulman)
        - Typescript and mimeos (Box 221, Folder 3851)
        - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3852)
      - "Goodbye, Jake"
        - Early draft: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3853)
        - Revised draft: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3854)
      - "Goodwood Comes Back"
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3855)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3856)
      - "Her Own People"
        - Early draft: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3857)
        - Revised draft: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3858)
      - "How Willie Proudfit Came Home": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3859)
      - "Invitation to a Dance." Today's Woman (Box 222, Folder 3860)
      - "The Life and Work of Professor Roy Millen"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3861)
        - Revised typescript, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3862)
        - Second revised typescript (Box 222, Folder 3863)
      - "The Love of Elsie Barton"
        - Draft A: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3864)
        - Draft B: typescript, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3865)
        - Draft C (marked "old version"): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3866)
        - Draft D: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3867)
        - Draft E: typescript, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3868)
        - Draft F (incomplete): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3869)
      - "Munk." The Purple and Gold (Clarksville High School): photocopy (Box 222, Folder 3870)
      - "The Patented Gate and the Mean Hamburger"
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3871)
        - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3872)
      - "Prime Leaf." Reviews for American Caravan printing, 1948, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3873)
      - "Testament of Flood"
        - Draft A: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3874)
        - Draft B: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3875)
        - Draft C: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3876)
      - "The Unvexed Isles": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3877)
      - "When the Light Gets Green" (marked "1st draft"): typescript, corrected, 1933 (Box 222, Folder 3878)
      - Untitled story (incomplete): holograph, n.d (Box 222, Folder 3879)
    - Short Plays
      - "The Ballad of Billie Potts" (dramatic adaptation, Wisconsin College of the Air): mimeograph, corrected, 1952 (Box 222, Folder 3880)
      - "Ballad of a Sweet Dream of Peace"
        Preface
        - Holograph worksheets, [1970] (Box 222, Folder 3881)
        - Typescript, corrected, [1970] (Box 222, Folder 3882)
        - Draft A (incomplete): holograph, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3883)
        - Draft B (marked "early stage of, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3884)
        - text"): typescript, carbon
        - Draft C (as produced at Loeb Theater, Harvard University)
          - Copy 1: typescript, photocopy, [1971] (Box 222, Folder 3885)
          - Copy 2 (marked "Final: Sept. 1, 1971"): typescript, photocopy (Box 222, Folder 3886)
          - Copy 3: typescript, [1971] (Box 222, Folder 3887)
          - Copy 4: typescript, corrected, [1971] (Box 222, Folder 3888)
          - Copy 5: typescript, photocopy, corrected, [1971] (Box 222, Folder 3889)
        - Draft D (marked "Version 2"): typescript, carbon, corrected, [1971] (Box 222, Folder 3890)
        - Draft E (marked "Version 3"): typescript, carbon, corrected, [1971] (Box 222, Folder 3891)
        - Draft F (marked "V-3"): typescript and carbon, corrected, [1971] (Box 222, Folder 3892)
        - Draft G (marked "V-3"); typescript, [1971] (Box 222, Folder 3893)
        - Draft H (photocopy of printed text and score):
          - Copy 1 (marked "final vers."), n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3894)
          - Copy 2 (marked "Master Copy"), n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3895)
        - Scores by Alexei Haieff (marked "earlier" and "later" scores): photocopies of holograph scores (Box 222, Folder 3896)
      - ["Natchez"]
        Source material
        - Joseph Hergesheimer. "Natchez" (Box 223, Folder 3897)
          - (story): typescript, 1934
          - Jo Swerling and Jan Fortune. "Natchez" (screenplay): typescript, 1940 Apr 5 (Box 223, Folder 3898)
        - Typescript, corrected (marked "RPW's treatment for tentative screen play"), n.d. (Box 223, Folder 3899)
        - Revised typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 3900)
    - Poems
      - "Acquaintance with Time in Autumn": holograph and typescript (Box 223, Folder 3901)
      - "Address of Soul to Body": setting typescript ( New Yorker ), 1971 (Box 223, Folder 3902)
      - "Adieu Sentimentale": typescript, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 3903)
      - "Admonition to the Dead" (two versions): typescript, 1923, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 3904)
      - "Admonition to Those Who Mourn": typescript, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 3905)
      - "After Teacups": typescript, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 3906)
      - "After Restless Night": typescript, carbon (Box 223, Folder 3907)
        See also: Box 228, folder 4223
      - "After the Dinner Party": holograph and typescript, corrected (several versions), 1983, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 3908)
      - "Aging Man in Woodland at Timeless Noon of Summer" (several versions): holograph and typescripts, corrected (Box 223, Folder 3909)
      - "Aging Painter Sits Where the Great Tower Heaves Down Midnight"
        - Draft A: holograph and typescript, 1980 Nov (Box 223, Folder 3910)